## SENTHIL SELVAKUMAR

https://www.linkedin.com/in/senthil-selvakumar-9815a8125

201-993-2892

https://github.com/Senthilselva/

senthilselvak@gmail.com

https://senthilselvak.herokuapp.com/

Full Stack Web Developer, with passion for all aspects of web development. Extensively well versed with both frontend and backend development, specializing in JavaScript, JQuery HTML, CSS, Bootstrap and Media Queries, Node.js and have an innate love for learning new NPM packages. Familiar with MVC file structure. Have strong experience with Relational Databases - MySQL and Oracle and also have a good understanding of Firebase database.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Node.js, Express, JavaScript, jQuery, GIT, Github, MySQL, Firebase, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Media Queries, APIs, JSON, REST, AJAX,ReactJS, MVC file structure.

## **EDUCATION**

Rutgers University Certificate, Full Stack Web Development

Fairleigh Dickinson University, New Jersey Masters of Science, Computer Science

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

AJS Associates Inc 2009 - Present

# Office Manager /I.T. Specialist

Planned and implemented computerized paper flow system of current files on all employees, bids, contract information, material cut sheet, bid documents etc. that helped the company to be more organized. Prepared invoice, certified payroll and processed payroll on a weekly basis. Managed daily Administrative affairs and communication

## Remin Technologies, LLC

2005 - 2009

## HR Manager

Founded and managed a C to C consulting corporation and hiring firm specializing in training and employee placement in the software industry.

**Cap Gemini** 2000 - 2004

## Software Developer

Worked on various telecommunication project as consultant for AT&T and Lucent Technologies. Used C++, Oracle and Unix

#### APPLICATIONS BUILT

## Resume Builder

2016 Full Stack Developer

• Application designed for young adults searching for volunteer, community service, internship, and part-time positions

(C)

# SENTHIL SELVAKUMAR

- Returns search results based on specific categories selected from user profile creation
- Provides email when position is selected
- Uses MySql, Sequelize, Handlebar, Node.js, Express, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript
- https://github.com/link-here / Heroku hosting

## **Face the Music**

2016 Full Stack Developer

- Built a mood based play-list generator
- Solely responsible creating firebase login, the embedding filepicker API which can be used for selecting a picture from the computer or take a picture from the camera, Firebase storage to store pictures and firebase database to store user information, for data validation using JQuery and JavaScript on my team
- <a href="https://github.com/link-here">https://github.com/link-here</a> / Firebase hosting